hooktheory.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy - Hooktheory

### Last updated May 25, 2018

* * *

Hooktheory.com is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring that you have a positive experience on our website. We know that you care how information about you is used and shared. We value your trust, and we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is managed carefully and sensibly.

This privacy policy describes our practices for handling both non-identifying and identifying (i.e., “personal”) information, including online and offline data. This policy applies only to the hooktheory.com website. Please note that BY VISITING HOOKTHEORY.COM, YOU ARE ACCEPTING THE PRACTICES DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY

## What is "personal information"? What personal information does Hooktheory collect?

"Personal information" is information that others, like hooktheory.com, can use to identify you. To create your user account at hooktheory.com, you will need to provide information that identifies you so that we can ensure that others cannot access your hooktheory.com account. You will be asked to provide only your e-mail address.

Please note that Hooktheory does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have collected such information we will delete it from our library. Children aged 13 or older should not submit any personal information without the permission of their parents or guardians. By using hooktheory.com, you are representing that you are at least 18, or that you are at least 13 years old and have your parents' permission to use the service. 

Upon request we provide users with access to all information that is maintained on them by Hooktheory.

## What does Hooktheory do with the information it collects?

Hooktheory uses the information you provide to help us improve and customize your online experience in some of the following ways:

  * to verify your identity when you login to your hooktheory.com account;
  * to process and deliver the services you order;
  * to give you the ability to create your personal hooktheory.com profile and view your protected personal information;
  * to provide support and assistance for our services;
  * to provide customer feedback and support;
  * to learn what you like and don't like, so we can personalize our website to fit your preferences;
  * to send emails with updates and information on Hooktheory's services
  * to meet legal obligations

## Does Hooktheory share my information with others?

Hooktheory respects the privacy of your information. We may provide your personal information to third parties for limited purposes, including but not limited to:

  * providing customer support;
  * enabling data processing and storage;
  * hosting websites;
  * maintaining hooktheory.com's privacy and security policies.
  * We use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Site--you can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information [here.](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) You can also opt-out of Google Analytics [here.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

#### As part of Compliance with the GDPR, Hooktheory has entered into data processing agreement (DPA's) with the following entities:

  * Linode - our web host
  * Google (Analytics) - tracking site usage statistics
  * MailChimp - for sending emails to our users information about our services
  * Stripe - payment processing gateway
  * Paypal - payment processing gateway

In rare cases we may be required to disclose your personal information by operation of law. For example, we reserve the right to disclose your personal information when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us. We may be required to transfer your personal information to a successor entity upon a merger, consolidation or other corporate reorganization in which Hooktheory participates or to a purchaser of all or substantially all of Hooktheory’s assets.

Otherwise, Hooktheory will never disclose your personal information to third parties unless you give us permission to do so. We will not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your information to any other third parties, except as otherwise described in this privacy policy.

## Is my personal information secure?

Yes. Hooktheory is committed to protecting your personal information. We maintain industry-standard security technologies to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. 

## Notice of breach of security

If a security breach causes an unauthorized intrusion into our system that materially affects you, we will notify you.

## How long will Hooktheory keep my personal information?

Hooktheory will only keep your personal information as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or as required by applicable law. If you are a member of the European Union, as part of the GDPR you have the right to request access to this information and that it be deleted. We will comply with these requests within 30 days, which can be made by contacting support@hooktheory.com .

## What about cookies?

Like other websites that provide services customized to its individual users, hooktheory.com uses technologies such as cookies and log files so we can make your visit to our website easier and provide you with your own customized hooktheory.com experience. 

Please note that a cookie cannot read any personal data off your hard disk. Accepting the cookies used on our website may give us access to information about your choice of Internet browser and your preferences when you visit our website. If you choose not to accept cookies, you can disable cookies by turning them off in your browser. Please note that this may disable some of the services and features when you visit hooktheory.com. 

## What if Hooktheory decides to use my information in a different way. 

From time to time, Hooktheory may use user information for new, innovative and unanticipated purposes not previously disclosed or described in this privacy policy. You will be notified by email of any changes to our privacy policy, which will also be posted on the hooktheory.com web site.

If you are concerned about how we are using your information, please check our web site periodically. Your continued use of this site  will constitute your acceptance thereof.

## What about other websites linked to hooktheory.com?

Hooktheory provides links to other web sites. Hooktheory is not responsible for the privacy practices or content on other web sites. We strongly suggest that you read a website’s privacy policy before submitting personal information or utilizing the resources of that site.
